Masashi Kondo

Senior Software Engineer

(000)-000-0000 | Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada linkedin.com/in/masashi-kondo | github.com/MssKnd

SUMMARY

As a Software Engineer with over 10 years of experience specializing in Web Frontend, I excel in developing responsive, performant, and accessible applications with React, TypeScript, and ES6. automated testing (unit, integration, E2E), semantic HTML, CI/CD (GitHub Actions), GraphQL, and progressive web apps. Adept at aligning technical solutions with business goals and driving team productivity through effective agile methodologies. Speaker at GDG DevFest 2020 Tokyo.

EXPERIENCE

CEO / Full Stack Software Engineer (Self-employed)

Jun 2022 – Present

Rokka LLC

Kumamoto, Japan

- Built responsive, accessible, secure, and performant web applications with React and TypeScript, implementing robust automated testing (unit, integration, E2E).
- Optimized frontend performance significantly, reducing rendering times and memory usage for mobile-first applications.
- Designed and implemented a Design System to ensure consistency and efficiency in UI/UX.
- As a Scrum Master, enhanced Scrum events' efficiency, doubling meeting productivity and improving feedback cycles, resulting in a 20% increase in overall team productivity.

Software Engineer / Web Frontend Engineer Safie Inc.

Dec 2018 – Mar 2022

- Created interactive and performant web-based video viewing applications optimized for diverse devices, including mobile, leveraging Angular and modern CSS techniques.
- Integrated frontend solutions with machine learning capabilities, demonstrating cross-domain collaboration and iterative development.
- Successfully led the adoption of Scrum during the team's growth, overseeing velocity tracking and visualization to stabilize the development process.

Network Engineer

Jul 2013 – Dec 2018

 $SoftBank\ Corp.$

 $Tokyo,\ Japan$

Tokyo, Japan

- Maintained dedicated line systems and developed web applications.
- Designed and implemented business systems with VPN between international offices in 2 months.

Education

Master of Kansei Science

Apr 2011 – Mar 2013

Kyushu University

Bachelor of Science in Information Science (Computer Science Equivalent) Apr 2009 – Mar 2011 Kumamoto National College of Technology

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Frameworks & Libraries: Tools & Platforms: TypeScript, ES6, Deno, JavaScript, Kotlin, HTML/CSS

React, Angular, GraphQL, Next.js, jest, Storybook, Playwright, Spring boot Git, GitHub Actions (CI/CD), Node.js, Supabase, PostgreSQL, Figma.

Docker, AWS, IntelliJ IDEA, Cursor

Other:

CSS, Accessibility (a11y), Semantic HTML, Progressive Web Apps (PWA),

Web Performance Optimization, Web Standard API, Agile methodologies,

Notwork Technology, Security